(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
絶対的アイドル
卒業LIVE
THE ABSOLUTE IDOL
Graduation LIVE
AMANE KANATA
2025.12.27
ようこそ
★天音かなたの3D配信へ
Welcome
to Amane Kanata's 3D stream
はい、サイドチェストー！
Yes, side chest!
誰でも分かります
Anyone can tell
卒業
Graduation
出会えた
Meeting you...
奇跡に　もう息が止まりそうだよ
...was a miracle, it almost takes my breath away.
荒野のピース
作詞：澤田和也　作曲：菅野よう子
Piece of the Wilderness
Lyrics: Kazuya Sawada | Composition: Yoko Kanno
何を見ているの
What are you looking at...
どこまでも澄んだ瞳で
...with eyes as clear as can be?
二人だけが触れる世界で
In a world that only the two of us can touch,
きっと全てが今始まるから
surely everything is beginning now.
君に会うために生まれたこと
That I was born to meet you...
伝えたい想いだ
...is the feeling I want to convey.
涼やかな風も胸誘う
A cool breeze also beckons to my heart,
視線も全部
and my gaze, all of it...
ヒリヒリする声になるのさ　ずっと
...becomes a voice that tingles, always.
君を側に感じる
I feel you by my side.
濁りもない奇跡　持ち場は
In this clear moment of a miracle, my post is...
振り返るものなんてない
There's nothing to look back on.
二人きり未来さえ飛べるんだ
Just the two of us, we can even fly to the future.
どこへ行くの小さな
Where are you going?
自分に涙あふれるけど走り出せる
Tears overflow for my small self, but I can start running.
もしはぐれたら体ごと
If we get separated, with my whole body...
散ってみせる
...I'll show you I can bloom.
花びら舞った一夜の
Taking the form of the petals...
姿になって君の愛も貯めてサービスするよ　ずっと
...that danced for one night, I'll store up your love and give it back, always.
君はそう微笑む
You smile like that.
汚されない奇跡が
The miracle that won't be tainted...
時を超えて呼び合う
...calls out to each other across time.
二人きり未来へと飛ぶんだ
Just the two of us, we'll fly toward the future.
出会えた
Meeting you...
奇跡に　もう息が止まりそうだよ
...was a miracle, it almost takes my breath away.
繋いだ
In those joined...
その手に　少し強くなれる気がする
...hands, I feel like I can become a little stronger.
出会えた
Meeting you...
奇跡に　もう息が止まりそうだよ
...was a miracle, it almost takes my breath away.
明日も
Tomorrow...
未来も　ただどうしようもなく好きだよ
...and the future too, I just love you beyond help.
Oh oh oh oh oh oh...
ピースサイン
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Peace Sign
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
いつか僕らの上をすれすれに通り過ぎて行ったあの飛行機を
I remember that airplane that once passed
right above our heads
不思議なくらいに覚えてる　意味もないのに何故か
It's strange how I remember it,
even though there's no reason why
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に　ただ強くなりたいと願ってた
On the night I cried from feeling pathetic,
I only wished to become stronger
そのために必要な勇気を　探し求めていた
I was searching for the courage
I needed to do that
残酷な運命が定まってるとして
Even if a cruel fate is already decided
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
And if it were to appear before me someday
ただ一瞬、この一瞬、息ができないなら
If for just an instant, this instant,
I can't even breathe
どうでもいいと思えた　その心を
Then I won't care about anything else,
and that heart...
もう一度　遠くへ行け　遠くへ行け
Go further once more, go further!
僕の中で誰かが歌う　どうしようもないほど熱烈に
Someone is singing inside of me
with an uncontrollable passion
いつだって目を腫らした君が　二度と悲しまないように笑える
So that you, who always has swollen eyes,
can smile and never be sad again
そんなヒーローになるための歌
This is a song to become that kind of hero
さらば掲げろ　ピースサイン
So, farewell, hold up a peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
To this story as it rolls along
守りたいだなんて言えるほど　君が弱くはないの分かってた
I knew you weren't weak enough
for me to say I wanted to protect you
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ　君が大事だったんだ
But I was even weaker than that,
and you were important to me
独りで生きてくんだなんてさ　口を突いて叫んだあの日から
Since the day I blurted out
that I would live on my own
変わっていく僕を笑えばいい　独りが怖い僕を
You can laugh at how I've changed,
at how I'm afraid of being alone
蹴飛ばして噛み付いて息もできなくて
Kicking, biting, and unable to breathe
騒ぐ頭とお腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
Even if my racing head
and the pit of my stomach become a mess
てらいも外聞も消えてしまうくらいに
To the point where bashfulness
and reputation both disappear
今は触っていたいんだ　君の心に
Right now, I want to be touching your heart
僕たちはきっといつか遠く離れた
We will surely reach out someday
太陽にすら手が届いて　夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
Even to the distant sun,
and let's laugh as we seize the dawn
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり　おぼろげな街の向こうへ
Stained in a blue burning color,
beyond the hazy city
手を繋いで走っていけるはずだ
We should be able to run, holding hands
君と未来を盗み描く　捻りのないストーリーを
Stealing a glimpse of the future with you,
a story with no twists
瘡蓋だらけ荒れくれた日々が　削り削られ擦り切れた今が
Days full of scabs and roughness,
a present that's been chipped and worn away
君の言葉で蘇る　鮮やかにも現れていく
They're revived by your words,
appearing vividly before me
蛹のままで眠る魂を　食べかけのまま捨てたあの夢を
The soul sleeping in its cocoon,
the dream I threw away half-eaten
もう一度取り戻せ
Take them back once more!
Oh oh oh oh oh oh...
もう一度　遠くへ行け　遠くへ行け
Go further once more, go further!
僕の中で誰かが歌う　どうしようもないほど熱烈に
Someone is singing inside of me
with an uncontrollable passion
いつだって目を腫らした君が　二度と悲しまないように笑える
So that you, who always has swollen eyes,
can smile and never be sad again
そんなヒーローになるための歌
This is a song to become that kind of hero
さらば掲げろ　ピースサイン
So, farewell, hold up a peace sign
転がっていくストーリーを
To this story as it rolls along
君と未来を盗み描く　捻りのないストーリーを
Stealing a glimpse of the future with you,
a story with no twists
考えたってわからないし　青空の下君を待った
Thinking about it won't help me understand,
I waited for you under the blue sky
風が吹いた正午　昼下がりを抜け出す想像
At noon when the wind blew,
imagining escaping the early afternoon
ねぇ、これからどうなるんだろうね　進め方教わらないんだよ
Hey, what will happen from now on?
I wasn't taught how to move forward
君の目を見た　何も言えず僕は歩いた
I looked into your eyes,
and I walked on without saying a word
だから僕は音楽を辞めた
作詞・作曲：n-buna
That's Why I Gave Up on Music
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
考えたってわからないし　青春なんてつまらないし
Thinking about it won't help me understand,
and youth is just boring anyway
辞めたはずのピアノ　机を弾く癖が抜けない
The piano I was supposed to have quit,
I can't stop the habit of playing on my desk
ねぇ、将来何してるだろうね　音楽はしてないといいな
Hey, I wonder what I'll be doing in the future?
I hope I'm not doing music
困らないでよ　心
Don't be troubled, my heart
喉の奥に
In the back of my throat
バツを引いても どうしても消えなかった
Even if I cross it out, it just won't disappear.
今更なんだから何も 思い出すな
It's too late now, so don't remember a thing.
間違ってるんだよ わかってないよ あんたら人間も
You're wrong, you don't understand, you humans too.
本当も愛も世界も 苦しさも人生も どうでもいいよ
Truth, love, the world, pain, and life—I don't care about any of it.
正しいかどうか知りたいのだって 防衛本能だ
Even wanting to know if it's right is just a defense instinct.
考えたんだ あんたのせいで
I thought about it, because of you.
考えたってわからないが 本当に年老いたくないんだ
I think and think but I don't know, I really don't want to get old.
いつか死んだって思うだけで 胸が空っぽになるんだ
Just thinking that I'll die someday makes my heart feel empty.
将来何してるだろうって 大人になったらわかったよ
I wondered what I'd be doing in the future, and I found out once I became an adult.
何もしてないさ
I'm doing nothing at all.
幸せな顔した人が
Those people with happy faces—
憎いのはどう割り切ったらいいんだ
How should I come to terms with hating them?
満たされない頭の奥の
Deep inside my unsatisfied head,
化け物みたいだ 劣等感
this sense of inferiority is like a monster.
間違ってないよな 何だかんだ あんたら人間だ
I'm not wrong, right? One way or another, you're all humans.
愛も救いも優しさも 根拠がないなんて 君が悪いよ
Love, salvation, and kindness having no basis—it's your fault.
ラブソングなんかが 痛いのだって防衛本能だ
Even love songs hurting is just a defense instinct.
どうでもいいか あんたのせいで
Is it whatever? Because of you.
考えたってわからないし
I think and think but I don't know,
生きてるだけでも苦しいし
and even just living is painful.
音楽とかもうわかんないし
I don't even understand music anymore,
歌詞とか適当でもいいよ
so the lyrics can be whatever.
どうでもいいんだ
I don't care about anything.
間違ってないだろ
I'm not wrong, right?
間違ってないよな
間違ってるんだよ わかってんだ あんたら人間も
You're wrong, I know it, you humans too.
本当も救いも優しさも 人生もどうでもいいんだ
Truth, salvation, kindness, and life—I don't care about any of it.
正しい答えが言えないの だって防衛本能だ
Being unable to give the right answer is just a defense instinct.
どうでもいいや あんたのせいで
I don't care, because of you.
僕だって信念があった 今じゃゴミみたいな思いだ
I had convictions too; now they're thoughts like trash.
何度でも君を書いた
I wrote about you over and over.
売れることこそが どうでもよかったんだ
Selling well didn't matter to me at all.
本当だ 本当なんだ 昔はそうだった
It's true, it really is true; it used to be like that.
だから僕は
That's why I...
だから僕は音楽を辞めた
That's why I quit music.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラとたぎれ
Burn, burn brightly.
眠っているだけの正義
The justice that was just sleeping—
こんな僕も
even someone like me
君のヒーローになりたいのさ
wants to be your hero.
Mela!
かっこいい君には
To the cool you,
僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
I wonder if I'm unreliable.
そりゃそうだよな だって
That's only natural, because
今もこうして迷ってる
even now, I'm lost like this.
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブアンドテイクさ
It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero.
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラとたぎる
Burning brightly,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
the justice hidden even in me,
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
look, before I knew it, I was holding your hand.
いったい全体 そんなに荷物を
Why on earth are you carrying
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
so much baggage and where are you going?
ねえねえ待って
Hey, hey, wait.
僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Why don't you try entrusting a bit to me?
信じてばかりの僕と
And me, who only keeps on believing—
信じることが怖い君と
With you, who's afraid of believing,
どちらが正しいのかなんて
as for which of us is right,
誰にもわからないさ
nobody can really know.
La la la la...
僕らだけの世界
A world only for us,
Give and take さ
it's all give and take.
補い合えた暁には
Once we can complement each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want us to dream the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて 独りぼっちにさせたのは
Painfully calling you 'cool' and leaving you all alone,
少し僕のせいなんだよな
that was partly my fault, wasn't it?
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But reality is what we must face,
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
now it's my turn to save you.
抱えないで 信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't hold it all in; I want you to trust and lean on me.
今なんじゃない メラメラとたぎる
Isn't it now? Burning and seething,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
even in me, there's a hidden sense of justice.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable urge,
ほら気づけば手を握っている
look, before I know it, I'm holding your hand.
放っとけない
I can't leave you be,
そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
where are you going carrying such a heavy load?
ほんのちょっと 僕にちょっと預けてみては
Just a little, why not let me carry some of it?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Someone like me wants to be your hero, too.
La la la la...
はーい！皆さん！
Hi, everyone!
とうとう始まってしまいました！
It's finally begun!
天音かなた卒業ライブということでですね
This is Amane Kanata's Graduation Live!
こちら、ハッシュタグがですね
The hashtag for today...
あの #天音かなた卒業ライブ でございますんで
is #AmaneKanataGraduationLive,
ぜひこちら、よろしくお願いいたします
so please use it to share your thoughts.
1曲目に歌った「今夜のヒンス」は
The first song, 'Konya no Hince'...
実は初配信で歌おうか
I was actually torn whether to sing it
悩んでいた楽曲だったので
during my very first stream,
ここで歌えて、すごく良かった
so I'm really glad I could sing it here.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
小さい頃からね、ヒロインよりヒーローに
Since I was little, I've always wanted to be a hero
なりたーいっていうタイプだったので
rather than a heroine,
そういった楽曲をたくさん歌わせていただきました
so I've sung many songs with that theme.
ありがとね、みんな拍手もありがとう！
Thank you, and thanks for the applause too!
次からは、ロックで感情ぶつけていくような歌を
Next, I'll be singing rock songs to let my emotions out.
調節しますんで... あ、マイクがね
I'll adjust... Oh, the mic stand...
調節しますんで
I'll adjust it now.
聴いてください、「劣等上等」！
Please listen to 'Bring It On'!
Yeah!
劣等上等
Bring It On
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
劣等上等 BRING IT ON!
Inferiority is fine, BRING IT ON!
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
劣等上等 踏み込め
Inferiority is fine, step forward!
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Child's play mathematics,
バレてんだってそんなんプライドがない
I see through it; there's no pride in that.
媚びへつらい お飾りで
Flattery and mere decorations,
髪の毛一本ばかりじゃつまんねー
just a single hair is so boring.
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Look, more mistakes are just fine,
退屈に手をかけて
give boredom a piece of your mind.
ママ、やっぱ私は
Mama, after all, I...
こんなところじゃ終われない
can't let it end in a place like this.
ぬるい敵が震えそう
Weak enemies seem ready to tremble,
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
goodbye to playing house and acting.
ずっとこのままなんてさ
Staying like this forever is...
いらないよ
unnecessary.
だっだっだ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm becoming an adult,
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて
experiencing both the sour and the sweet.
ぱっぱっぱ 変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa, in this changing era,
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
it's not all bad things, is it?
過去も今もすべてを 繋げて歩いていきたいや
Connecting past and present, I want to keep walking.
超えろはー
Surpass it all—
ほら 挑発 私達は脳濁
Look, a provocation, our brains are foggy,
緑のアイツにバカかまって
wasting time on that green guy.
さあ どーなっつ いつまでもどうか
Now, donuts, forever and somehow,
仰いでよ どこが残念なんですか？
look up, what exactly is so unfortunate?
劣等　上等　やってやろうじゃん
Inferiority? Bring it on! Let's do this.
コンプレックスさえも味方に
Turning even my complexes into allies.
冗談じゃなく
No joke.
中指立てたくなるような
The kind of situation that makes you want to flip them off...
事情ありすぎて指が足りねえ
...there are so many I don't have enough fingers.
Hands up! What’s up? 最低な
Hands up! What’s up? This terrible...
状況を笑え
...situation, just laugh it off!
ママ、パパ、何にもいらない
Mama, Papa, I don't need anything.
欲しがります死ぬまでは
I'll keep wanting things until the day I die.
飛び出せさあ今夜
Let's jump out tonight.
たまに投げ出すのもいいから
Because it's okay to give up sometimes.
覚悟しておけよ
You'd better be ready.
ダッダッダ
Da-da-da.
僕ら大人になるために
For us to become adults,
散々
Thoroughly,
狙い定めていたい日々に
In the days when I want to keep my aim steady.
燦々
Brilliantly,
ぶちかませ進撃だ
Let it rip, it's an all-out attack!
前を向けよ　さあ今だ
Look forward, now's the time!
いつも
Always,
夢を
Your dreams,
捨てて
Discarding them,
行かないで　伝えたいよ
Don't go yet, I want to tell you.
ダッダッダ
Da-da-da.
くだらないことばかり譲れない
I won't back down on all these trivial things.
わかるか　私の美学
Do you understand my aesthetic?
この場所自負したい
I want to take pride in this place.
拳一つが　唯一なんて
With just a single fist as my only...
切り札　愚直なんて
...trump card, so straightforward.
殻破れさあ
Break out of your shell, now!
一撃 KO だらば
With a single-blow KO!
こんなもんじゃない
It's not just this.
ダッダッダ
Da-da-da.
私大人になる前に
Before I become an adult,
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
I've tasted the bitter and the sweet, and now,
燦々
Brilliantly,
交わる未体験を
This intersecting unknown experience.
前を向けよ　さあ今だ
Look forward, now's the time!
時代
The times,
回って
Keep spinning,
くれよ
For me!
全て飲み込んでやるから
Because I'm going to swallow it all up!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
それでは皆様お先に Bye
Well then, everyone, I'll be going now, bye!
フロアが沸き上がりました
The floor has heated up!
ぼくらの16bit戦争 / 作詞・作曲:sasakure.UK
Our 16bit War / Lyrics & Composition: sasakure.UK
どうしてこんなことになったんだ
Why did it turn out like this?
誰も教えてはくれないんだ
No one will tell me.
何が正義だ
What is justice?
何が犠牲だ
What is sacrifice?
秩序は僕を裏切った
Order has betrayed me.
始めは小さな穴だったんだ
It was just a small hole at first.
居心地だけは良かったのにな
Even though it felt so comfortable.
プロパガンダと呑み合うダイヤ
Diamonds and propaganda swallowing each other up.
あら次第に巨大化した
Oh, it gradually grew huge.
そう　ライトでデッドな方は水蒸気
Yes, those on the right and dead are water vapor.
都合良すぎた大人たちの都合に
To the convenience of adults who were too convenient.
ひとつまたひとつ未来は
One by one, the future...
過去を無視した
...ignored the past.
65,535のテトラと
With 65,535 tetras...
0次元の理想を抱いていてもなお
...and holding onto 0-dimensional ideals, even still,
ひとつまたひとつエレメントは
One by one, the elements...
姿を消した
...disappeared.
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16bit war.
遂にあの波に飲まれるな
Finally, don't let that wave swallow you up.
残された空間幕末
The remaining space at the end of the curtain.
不覚に弾きさえつきゃしない
I can't even get a shot off in my carelessness.
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16bit war.
有ると無いとが交差する
Existence and non-existence cross paths.
1と0しか愛せない僕
I, who can only love 1s and 0s,
何を信じて生きればいい
What should I believe in and live for?
もっと速い猛火潜り
Diving through even faster raging fires.
レジスタすらを一斉掃射
Simultaneously firing upon even the registers.
無言圧力　数の暴力
Silent pressure, the violence of numbers.
鋼に打ち込めよトコトコ
Strike it into the steel, tokotoko
虚空の警笛 肩越しに響く駆形
The whistle of the void, a square wave echoing over my shoulder
放たれた断末 アルカディアの鐘が鳴る日は
A released death rattle, on the day the bells of Arcadia ring
来るのだろうか
Will it ever come?
僕らの16bit戦争
いいね あの波に飲まれるな
Our 16-bit war
Alright, don't let those waves swallow you up
残された狂鳴も僕ら
今日も狂い眠りがしない
Even the remaining mad echoes,
We're going crazy again today, unable to sleep
僕らの16bit戦争
有ると問え 伍が交差する
Our 16-bit war
Ask if it exists, as the groups cross paths
ビートダウン 尾米との先で
僕は秩序触れられない
Beatdown, at the end of the grain,
I cannot touch order
僕らの16bit戦争
世界を敵に回しても
Our 16-bit war
Even if we turn the whole world against us
表現できない もどかしさに
晒されることが何より不幸だった
Being exposed to the frustration of being unable to express ourselves was the greatest misfortune of all
僕らの16bit戦争
Our 16-bit war
はい。
Yes.
皆さん、ありがとうございます。
Thank you, everyone.
ここにね、何があると思います？
What do you think is here?
水。
Water.
トレンド1位って本当ですかこれ？
Is it true we're trending at number one?
嘘かもしれませんけれども。本当かな？
It might be a lie, but... is it true?
ガチかも。
Maybe for real.
ありがとう、みんな。
Thank you, everyone.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
かっこいいと言ってくれてるのを見ながら...
While seeing everyone saying it's cool...
メガホンマイクが手からすっぽ抜けかけましたよ。本当に。
the megaphone mic almost slipped out of my hand. Seriously.
焦ったわー。
I was panicking.
ということでね、えーっと。
So, anyway, um...
何かに挑んでいく曲みたいなのが好きなので、もともと。
I've always liked songs where you're challenging something.
「劣等上等」と「僕らの16bit戦争」を歌わせていただきました！
I performed 'Bring It On' and 'Our 16bit Wars'!
ね、すごい大好きなかっこいい楽曲たちなので、ぜひぜひ原曲もチェックしてみてください！
They're such cool songs that I love, so please go check out the original versions as well!
ちょっと待って。
Wait a sec.
僕、VTuberなんで着替えは何秒かかると思う？
I'm a VTuber, so how many seconds do you think it takes me to change?
1秒だ！
One second!
ほれ。
Look.
すごいやろ？
Amazing, right?
これがVTuber、バーチャルアイドルね。
This is a VTuber, a virtual idol.
では、このまま続けていくぞー！
Now then, let's keep going!
ローリンガール / 作詞・作曲: wowaka
Rolling Girl / Lyrics & Composition: wowaka
ロンリーガールはいつまでも
The lonely girl is always
届かない夢見て
Dreaming of a dream she can't reach
騒ぐ頭の中を
The noise inside her head
かき回して かき回して
Stir it up, stir it up
「問題ない」と呟いた
"No problem," she muttered
言葉は失われた？
Were the words lost?
失敗 失敗 間違い探しに終われば
Failure, failure, if it ends with searching for mistakes
また回るの！
It'll spin again!
もう一回 もう一回 私は今日も転がりますと
One more time, one more time, I'll roll again today, so
少女は言う 少女は言う 言葉に意味を奏でながら
The girl says, the girl says, as she plays the meaning of the words
もう一回 まだですよ まだまだ先は見えないので
One more time, not yet, since I still can't see what's ahead
息を止めるの 今
I'll hold my breath, now
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The end of the road for the rolling girl
届かない向こう側
The other side she can't reach
色の、重なる声と声を
...colors, the voices that layer over each other,
混ぜあわせて、混ぜあわせて。
Mix them together, mix them together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた言葉は、失われた。
"No problem," she muttered, but the words were lost.
どーなったっていいんだってさ、間違いだって起こしちゃおうとさ
She says it doesn't matter what happens, let's just make a mistake
誘う坂道
On this inviting slope...
もう一回、もう一回。私をどうか転がして
One more time, one more time. Please, keep me rolling
と少女は言う、少女は言う。無口に意味を重ねながら
So says the girl, so says the girl. Layering meaning into her silence
もう一回、もう少し。もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと
One more time, just a bit more. "I'll see something soon," she said
息を止めるの、今。
I'll hold my breath, right now.
もう一回、もう一回。私は今日も転がりますと
One more time, one more time. "I'll keep rolling again today," she says
と少女は言う、少女は言う。言葉に意味を奏でながら
So says the girl, so says the girl. Playing with the meaning of her words
「もう良いかい？」 「もう少し、そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
"Are you ready yet?" "Just a bit more, you're probably getting tired soon, right?"
息を止めるよ、今。
I'll stop my breath, right now.
誰も見ていない夢を見ろ
Nobody Sees the Dream I See
作詞・作曲：ビッケブランカ / 編曲：THE CHARM PARK
Lyrics/Composition: Vicke Blanka / Arrangement: THE CHARM PARK
今度こそ生き返れない、そう思った
I thought, "This time, I won't come back to life"
ベッドの中、気付けばカーテンの隙間から
In my bed, I noticed that through the gap in the curtains
朝が正解を教えた
Morning told me the answer
ああ、生きてたと安堵
Ah, the relief of being alive
ああ、生きてしまったと絶望
Ah, the despair of having survived
まだやれるのかな
Can I still do this?
まだやらなきゃなのかな
Do I still have to keep going?
いっそバリアーも変えてしまえば
If only I could just change the barrier too
なんてね
Just kidding
「僕は元気です。」そう言って今日も笑って
Saying, "I'm doing fine," and laughing again today
心はガラガラ大袈裟な音がする
My heart makes a rattling, exaggerated sound
週末の鐘の音か
Is that the sound of the weekend bell?
それでもこの声が、それでもこの口が
Even so, this voice... even so, this mouth...
それでもこの喉が
Even so, this throat...
千切れるくらい叫ぶよ
Will scream until it tears
この腕が、真っ白なこの羽が
These arms... these pure white wings...
僕のこの命が
This life of mine...
生きたいと歌ってる
Is singing, "I want to live!"
できるなら愛されたい、許されたい
If I can, I want to be loved, I want to be forgiven
ここにいたい、愛したい
I want to be here, I want to love
誰も見ていない夢を見るよ
I'll see the dream that nobody else sees
だから僕を見ていろよ
So keep your eyes on me!
感情の捨て方は、粗大ゴミのシールを貼る
The way to throw away emotions is to stick a "bulky waste" sticker on them
本音はいつも強がりの裏
My true feelings are always behind my bravado
潰れる音がするんだ
I can hear the sound of them being crushed
ああ、気付かれなかった
Ah, nobody noticed
ああ、気付いてほしいんだ
Ah, I want you to notice
それでも君が笑ってくれるなら
Even so, if you will smile for me
いっそ心を失くしてしまえば
If only I could just lose my heart entirely
なんてね
Just kidding
「叶わない」なんて、一瞬でも思ったら負けだ
"It won't come true" — if I think that for even a second, I've lost
「叶わない」なんて、一瞬でもよぎれば辞めだ
"It won't come true" — if that even crosses my mind, I'll quit
何万通の諦める理由があったとしても
Even if there were tens of thousands of reasons to give up
たった一つの、勇気がこの手の中に
I have just one piece of courage in my hands
それでもこの声が、それでもこの口が
Even so, this voice... even so, this mouth...
それでもこの喉が
Even so, this throat...
千切れるくらい叫ぶよ
Will scream until it tears
この腕が、真っ白なこの羽が
These arms... these pure white wings...
僕のこの命が
This life of mine...
生きたいと歌ってる
Is singing, "I want to live!"
できるなら愛されたい、許されたい
If I can, I want to be loved, I want to be forgiven
ここにいたい、愛したい
I want to be here, I want to love
誰も見ていない夢を見るよ
I'll see the dream that nobody else sees
だから僕を...
So, look at me...
誰も見ていない夢を見せるよ
I'll show you a dream that no one has seen.
だから僕を信じて
So, believe in me.
はい！皆さん！今のは最後のオリジナル楽曲で
Hi, everyone! That was my final original song...
「誰も見ていない夢を見ろ」というね...
...titled "Daremo Miteinai Yume wo Miro" (See the Dream No One Has Seen).
本日24時にリリース！わー！
It's being released today at midnight! Yay!
こちらのジャケットをですね、頼りに探してくださいね、各所。
Look for this cover art to find it on various platforms.
いや、この曲あまりにも卒業ソングすぎるって思ったでしょ？
You probably thought this song sounds way too much like a graduation song, right?
これ実は卒業決める前に作られていた曲で、卒業決める前に。
Actually, it was written before my graduation was decided. Before it was decided.
MVは明日ね、明日の20時、もうかなたそがいなくなっても
The MV will be released tomorrow at 8:00 PM. Even after Kanata-so is gone...
予約投稿というものがある、ネットには。
...there's this thing called scheduled uploads on the internet.
ということで明日の20時に投稿されるんですが、内容も実は卒業誰も知らずに作っているということで、
So it'll be posted tomorrow at 8:00 PM. The content was also made without anyone knowing about the graduation...
なんかこんな偶然の一致でそれっぽくなってしまいました。
...so it's quite a coincidence that it turned out like this.
それを踏まえてまた「なんでやねん」と思いながら聞いてください。
Knowing that, please listen to it again while thinking "Wait, what?"
ヒゲドライバーさんにね、作詞作曲していただいて、
It was written and composed by Hige Driver-san.
あの悪魔の子いっぱい歌ったりしたんで、超嬉しかったです。ありがとうございます。
He's the one who did "Akuma no Ko" which I've sung a lot, so I was super happy. Thank you!
そしてですね、お次はグッズを紹介させていただきます！
And now, I'd like to introduce the merchandise!
こちら！はい！天音かなた卒業グッズがもう出てます！
Here they are! Yes! Amane Kanata graduation goods are already available!
なんと出てる！ということで、それでは一つずつ見ていきましょう！
They're out! So, let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！はい！アクリルパネルです！
First, this! Yes! An acrylic panel!
可愛いでしょ？じゃん！
Isn't it cute? Ta-da!
こちらね、おしおママに思いを伝えた上で、描き下ろしていただいたイラストになっております。
This is an illustration newly drawn by Oshio-mama after I shared my thoughts with her.
本当にね、みんなに対して最後はまあ笑顔かなとか、
I thought that for the end, I should be smiling for everyone...
青い薔薇というものを最初からちょっとモチーフ的に入れたりすることがあったので、
...and since I've used blue roses as a motif from the start...
こちらでもまた入れていただきました。
...I had her include them here as well.
可愛いでしょ？笑顔にしてもらいました。
Isn't it cute? I asked her to make me smile.
お次は、こちら！じゃん！じゃん！
Next up is this! Ta-da! Ta-da!
この、これすごい、かなた＆こなたのアクリルスタンドです。
This is amazing—a Kanata & Konata acrylic stand.
これもね、僕がね、本当にね、こなたという妹というものを
I really wanted to leave my sister, Konata, behind in this world...
ぜひこの世に残して生きてよ、ということで
...to live on, so...
僕が欲しいがために生まれたグッズでございます。
...this is a piece of merch born from my own desire for it.
可愛いでしょ？エロイよな。
Isn't it cute? It's kind of sexy, right?
ということで、次は、こちら！じゃん！
And next is this! Ta-da!
すっ、ボイスキーホルダーです！ボイスのね、
It's a voice keychain! For the voices,
6種は僕がオリジナル考えました。オリジナルっちゅうても、「へい、こんかなたー」とかだけのさ、じゃん！
I came up with the six original lines myself. Even if they're just things like "Hey, kon-kanata!" Ta-da!
で、このイラストもですね、僕原案を書いて、プロがすごいよくしてくれましたね。
I also drew the rough draft for this illustration, and the pros made it look great.
でもわかるでしょ、かなたその絵柄って。いや、ありがとうございますと。
But you can still see Kanata-so's art style in it, right? Thank you so much.
収録ボイスは届いてからのお楽しみです。いっぱいポチポチしてください。
The recorded voices are a surprise for when they arrive. Please click it a lot.
そして最後のグッズは、こちら！じゃじゃーん！
And the final item is this! Ta-da!
「あるてぃめっとへい民認定証」！
The "Ultimate Hey-min Certificate"!
これは最後まで応援してくれた究極のへい民、あるてぃめっとへい民の認定証です。
This is a certificate for the ultimate Hey-min who supported me until the end.
シリアルナンバーが入っていて世界で一枚です。
It has a serial number, so it's the only one of its kind in the world.
ちなみにちょっと、あのお買い得…じゃねえや、手が届きやすいので、
By the way, it's quite... not "a bargain", but affordable...
これだけでもぜひ皆さん、思い出によろしくお願いします。
...so I hope you'll consider getting just this one as a memento.
今までへい民じゃなかったけど、かなたーんって思った人も、あるてぃめっとへい民だからあんたは。
Even if you weren't a Hey-min before, if you feel for Kanata now, you're an Ultimate Hey-min too.
ということでですね、お次は、こちら特典ですね。
So, moving on, here are the bonuses.
はい、特典はポストカードになっております。
Yes, the bonus is a postcard.
数量限定が直筆サイン入りだったんですが、こちらはですね、
The limited-quantity version came with a handwritten signature...
12月24日の20時から発売開始しており、もう品切れ…ごめんなさい、完売しているんですけど、
...but they went on sale at 8:00 PM on Dec 24th and are already—sorry, they're sold out.
フルセットの方はまだありますので、箔押し複製サイン入ってますので、よろしくお願いします。
But the full set is still available and includes a foil-stamped replica signature, so please check it out.
ちょっとね、このフルセット特典の方は
For the full set bonus...
「寂しいよ」っていう気持ちがちょっと溢れ出し…ダラー…って感じになっております。
...I let my feelings of "I'm lonely" overflow into it... like a drip... or something.
はい、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Yes, I hope you like it.
ふー、すげー汗を...
Whew, I'm sweating so much...
かなたー！
Kanata!
サプライズ！サプライズです！
Surprise! It's a surprise!
かなたー！来てるんですけど！
Kanata! We're here!
え、かなた！ひどいよ！
What, Kanata! That's mean!
一人で辞めさせないよ！
We won't let you quit alone!
え、ゲストいないので...なんで...
Wait, I don't have any guests... why...
一人で辞めさせないよ！
We won't let you quit alone!
嘘、ちょっと、寂しいだろ、
No way, wait, it's lonely,
一人で辞めさせないよ、来るよ！
We won't let you quit alone, we're coming!
あっ、あ、あ、出てる！出てる！
Ah, ah, ah, they're appearing! They're appearing!
バクタレたちとマリンちゃんラミィちゃんころねちゃんがなんか来てくれました！
Bakutare and Marine-chan, Lamy-chan, Korone-chan... they all came to see me!
ええ！ありがとう！
Eh! Thank you!
え、ちょっと我々から渡したいものがありますよね？
Eh, we have something we'd like to give you, right?
何何何？マジで聞いてない、知らない、何？
What, what, what? I seriously didn't hear about this. I don't know, what?
マジで言ってない、マジで言ってない。
We seriously didn't tell you, seriously didn't tell you.
え、なんか、やだ、ちょっと。
Eh, wait, I don't like this (emotionally).
え、泣かせないで、ねえ、待って。
Eh, don't make me cry, hey, wait.
はい、どうぞー！
Here you go!
ありがとう。持てないか、持てないよね。
Thank you. I can't hold it, can I? It's too much.
あ、すごい！
Ah, amazing!
これ、三人で選んだ。
We three chose this together.
花束です。
It's a bouquet.
え、すごい、なんか、とても美しいバラみたいな感じの...
Eh, wow, it's like a really beautiful bunch of roses...
本当はね、バーチャル空間には映らないんだけど。
Actually, it doesn't show up in virtual space.
ちょっと映らないんですけど。
It's not really showing up.
僕だけのものです、みんな。
This is just for me, everyone.
え、すごい、こんなにデカい花束、もらったことない。
Eh, wow, I've never received such a huge bouquet.
じゃ、一旦回収します。
Well, we'll take it back for a moment.
あ、すいません、ありがとう。
Ah, sorry, thank you.
それとね、三人で寄せ書きもしまして。
And also, the three of us wrote a message board together.
ええー！すごーい！ありがとう！うれしい！
Eeeh! Amazing! Thank you! I'm so happy!
いや、こんなん、今見たら泣いちゃう。
Man, if I look at this now, I'll cry.
泣いちゃう、泣いちゃう。後でじっくりね。
You'll cry, you'll cry. Read it carefully later.
本当にありがとう。
Truly, thank you.
みんな、マジで、待って、本当にやだ。
Everyone, seriously, wait, I really don't like this.
本当にやだ、泣かせないで。
I really don't like it, don't make me cry.
やめる？やめるのやめる？
Stopping? Are you stopping stopping?
ここで、ここで、ここで、大円団にするんですけど。
Right here, right here, right here, it's going to be a grand finale.
じゃ、三人もしょってくれるってことで一緒に。
So, the three of you will also support me, together.
背負うよ、背負うよ。心強。
We'll carry it, we'll carry it. Reassuring.
明日初配信、明日初配信。
First stream tomorrow, first stream tomorrow.
そうだね、明日ね。切り替えて初配信しよう。
That's right, tomorrow. Let's switch gears and have the first stream.
切り替えていくか。いや、もう、ありがとう、みんな。
Guess I'll switch gears. Man, thank you everyone.
うるせえ...
You're so noisy...
めちゃめちゃ頼んだの、会いに来たいって。
I really begged them, saying I wanted them to come see me.
そうなの。もう、一人でなんか勝手にいろんなものさ、しょってさ。
That's right. You were just carrying so many things on your own.
そうだよ。やめていくなんて許せない。
Exactly. I can't forgive you for just leaving like that.
ありがとう。逃がさない。頼れよ、もっと。
Thank you. We won't let you get away. Rely on us more.
周りを頼れ！頼れ！頼れ！
Rely on those around you! Rely! Rely!
ありがとう。ありがとう。無理を言って今日駆けつけさせていただきました。
Thank you. Thank you. We asked for a lot and rushed here today.
本当に、本当に、本当に、すごいこと。
Really, really, really, it's an amazing thing.
ありがとうね。最後まで見るから。
Thank you. We'll watch until the end.
見てるからね！見ているからね！行っちゃうの？
We're watching! We're watching! You're going?
行かない、おめーだよ行くんは！
I'm not going, you're the ones leaving!
おめーが行くんだよ！おめーが行くんだよ！先に引くんじゃねーよ！
You're the ones leaving! You're the ones leaving! Don't pull back first!
ありがとう。行かない、見てるからね。
Thank you. Not going, we'll be watching.
ずっと見てるよ。頑張ってね、最後まで。
We'll watch forever. Do your best until the end.
まだ泣かないよ、まだあるからね。
I won't cry yet, there's still more to come.
戻ってきてんのね、今、本当にずっと。頼むよ、頑張れ。
You're coming back to yourself now, truly. We're counting on you, good luck.
ありがとうね。これからもずっと仲良くしてください。
Thank you. Please keep being friends with me forever.
当たり前だよ、一生友達だよ。
Of course, we're friends for life.
一生友達だよ！一生友達！これからもずっとだからね。
Friends for life! Friends for life! It'll be like this forever, okay?
当たり前だよ。縁側で語り明かそうね、おばあちゃんになっても。
Of course. Let's talk all night on the veranda, even when we're old grandmas.
そこで見てるから. ありがとう、頑張れ！
We'll be watching from there. Thank you, good luck!
大好きだぞ！大好き！大好きだよ！愛してるよ！頑張ってね！
We love you! Love you! Love you! Love you! Good luck!
ありがとう。またね、またね、またね...
Thank you. See you, see you, see you...
ゲストは呼べないけどダメだよーって言ってたんですけど、ころさんと、あずちゃんと、らみちゃんが来てくれました。
I said I couldn't invite guests and that it was a no-go, but Koro-san, AZKi-chan, and Lamy-chan came.
本当に、ありがとうございます。あの、それでは、ここから、オリジナル楽曲が続いていきます。
Truly, thank you very much. Now, from here, original songs will continue.
歌えるのはね、最後になってしまうんですが、だからこそ、心を込めて歌っていこうと思います。
This will be the last time I can sing them, so I'll sing with all my heart.
ちょっと、マジでびっくりした。本当にありがとう。もう本当に素晴らしい友達を持って幸せです。
Wait, I was seriously surprised. Truly, thank you. I'm so happy to have such wonderful friends.
ホロライブに会えてよかった。ということで、じゃあ、聞いてね。
I'm glad I could meet Hololive. So then, please listen.
きゅーぴっど。
Cupid
キミのキューピッドです　夢中、注、注
I'm your Cupid. Crazy about you, attention, attention
きっと夢に出てくる　注、注、注
I'll surely appear in your dreams. Attention, attention, attention
ぎゅっと抱きしめて
Hug me tight
インキャララバイ
Inkyara Lullaby
昨日待った着信音　ヤダヤダヤダヤダ
The ringtone I waited for yesterday. No no no no
強制終了トワイライト　ヤダヤダヤダヤダ
Forced termination twilight. No no no no
誰か止めてエレベーター　ヤダヤダヤダヤダ
Someone stop the elevator. No no no no
そう我らこそ陰の者
Yes, we are the ones in the shadows
笑おう笑おう　せめて笑おう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, at least let's laugh
アハハ　ウフフ　笑い飛ばせ
Ahaha Ufufu, laugh it off
来ない来ない　乾きまくり
Not coming, not coming, bone dry
反省反省　また反省だ
Reflection, reflection, reflecting again
鏡ですら目を逸らした
Even the mirror looked away
明日は今日より人間になりたい
Tomorrow I want to be more human than today
なりたい　なりたい　なりたい！
I want to be, I want to be, I want to be!
おやすみなさーい！
Good night!
DA・LI・LA
...と言っても当たり前じゃないのに
...Even so, it's not something to take for granted
You are クラッチでゾンビな可愛い子
You are a cute zombie child in the clutch
そうでしょう？
Don't you agree?
ここでSHOWね！
It's time for the show here!
ああ あなたに捧げるわ
Ah, I'll dedicate it to you
私の愛とやらを全て
All of what I call my love
この手は私を守る
These hands protect me
ただため在ったのね
They were just there for that purpose
だったら今に君と
In that case, with you now
どんな最良の希望を
What kind of best hope?
ラストはうんと飾りましょう
Let's decorate the end grandly
ちょびっと痛いくらいで
With just a little bit of pain
ちょいと少しだけ
Just a little, just a bit
DA・LI・LA 頭の切れ
DA-LI-LA, sharpness of mind
さあ 異常抜け出し 死ぬ腹 皆 暴れ
Come on, escape the abnormality, everyone go wild until you die
重ねドレッド ダム 撃てパッパ
Layered dreads, dam, fire away pappa
天の裁きは 殴られたのでしょう
Heaven's judgment must have been struck down
最を 再を 共存だ
Coexisting with the end and the rebirth
酔望かき混ぜ かくりを こちらおいでよ
Stir up your drunken desires, Hidden World, come this way
かたみを その瞳で
With those eyes as a memento
恐れず僕と歌おう
Sing with me without fear
パッパッパのパッパカサ
Pappa-pappa no pappakasa
巡り巡れよ 確定を落とし合おう
Go round and round, let's cast down our certainties
そろそろ終わりにしないか
Shall we bring it to an end soon?
今ならば美しい ほら
If it's now, it's beautiful, see?
君は今更戻れない
You can't go back anymore
愛してくれ 僕のことを
Please love me
どうか邪魔などしないで
Please, don't interfere
から 遠い遠い別世界まで
From here, all the way to a far, far away world
触れまいままに 幕が上がる
The curtain rises without even touching
ただまた会いたくて
I just wanted to see you again
あなたに この拍手を
To you, this applause
Knock it out!
無敵な愛愛愛愛だ
Invincible love, love, love, love
気取れほら キープ連れ
Look, put on airs, take the keep
気持ちいいじゃない
Doesn't it feel good?
意味合いたい
Wanting to make sense
朱心招待 壊せ クライ
Cinnabar heart invitation, break it, cry
アンロック アンロックもう
Unlock, unlock already
そんな傷つけたりしないで
Don't hurt me like that
こんな毒だらけの世界になっちゃって
The world has become so full of poison
ごめんね 大丈夫 安全圏に寄って
I'm sorry, it's okay, come to the safe zone
安心な世界にこうね
Let's go to a safe world
見捨てないから ずっと今日も
I won't abandon you, forever, today too
アンロック アンロック噛み
Unlock, unlock bite
痛い気持ちになれ
Become a painful feeling
根本的な善になるまで
Until you become fundamentally good
愛してあげるね
I'll love you
どんどんよく見て待って
Look closer and closer, and wait
ブツブツに恋で焦がして
Scorch it with love bit by bit
忘れちゃうくらい 笑っちゃうくらい
Enough to forget, enough to laugh
ちゃんと愛愛愛 LOVE YOU!
Properly, love-love-love LOVE YOU!
浅い息を吸い 音を立てるな
Breathe shallowly, don't make a sound
やつらに気づかれる前に
Before they notice you
殺す目を凝らし その時を待て
Focus your killing eyes, wait for the moment
すべては一瞬のために
Everything is for that one instant
デスリ覚悟しろ 最後の時だ
Prepare yourself, it's the end
おじけづくよな意気地なしだ
What a coward to be frightened
世界を変えるデッドショットを今
The deadshot that will change the world, now
カリスマの銘 打ってアイドルの子
Signed as a charisma, an idol child
傷全部打ち抜け
Shoot through all the wounds
ラスト ラスト
Last, last
トリック打ちの最高 再会 滅の世界で
The best trick shot, reunion, in a world of destruction
死に物狂い出す 死にきれないなら
If you can't die, go into a frenzy
刹那 鳴れ
Resound for an instant
すべてをこの一瞬にかけて放て ラストリゾート
Put everything into this moment and fire, Last Resort
僕のすべてを込めて放つ ラストリゾート
Firing with all of my being, Last Resort
あなたがくれた希望で
With the hope you gave me
約束の羽で今
With the promised wings, now
飛ばなくちゃ
I have to fly
ともに行く
Go together
誓いの先へ
Beyond the oath
こぼれる涙 遠く高く
Overflowing tears, far and high
今の僕は強くなれる
The current me can become strong
飛べるよ 信じて 飛べるよ
I can fly, believe me, I can fly
その先へ
To what lies ahead
...べるよ 楽園 永遠の
...calling out, to the eternal paradise
さらばまで あー
until we say farewell, ah—
きっと待って
Surely wait
でも
But
あーーーーー
Ah—————
はるかかなた
Far, far away
待って
Wait for me
世界で一番のアイドル
The number one idol in the world
思い出して
Remember back
出会った日のこと
to the day we first met
手を取って
I took your hand
僕らの旅が始まった
and our journey began
走って転んで
Even if we run and fall
涙を流しても
and shed many tears
気がつけばほら
Before I knew it, look
顔を合わせて笑う
we're facing each other and laughing
喜ぶ声が嬉しくて
Your happy voices make me so glad
夢が溢れ出すね
dreams are starting to overflow
君がいなきゃだめなんだ
It has to be you
今世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番の笑顔をあげちゃう
I'll give you the number one smile in the world
僕を見つけてくれた
You found me
愛してくれた
You loved me
だからまだまだ終わらない
So it's not over yet
ちゃんと付いてきて
Make sure you keep up
きらめく夢
This sparkling dream
羽ばたいてゆく
Spreading my wings
背中を見送った
I watched your back as you left
雨上がり
After the rain
君の傘を返したら
once I've returned your umbrella
手を引いて進もう
Let's walk hand in hand
一緒にどこまでも
anywhere, together
気がつけばほら
Before I knew it, look
また前を向ける
I can look forward again
戯れ合う言葉の中にも
Even in our playful words
愛を感じています
I can feel the love
僕じゃなきゃだめなんでしょ？
It has to be me, right?
でしょ？
Right?
今世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番のときめきをあげちゃう
I'll give you the number one heartbeat in the world
僕を支えてくれた
You supported me
推してくれた
You cheered for me
だからまだまだ終わらない
So it's not over yet
隣にいてよ
Stay by my side
自信なんてない
I have no confidence
不安ばかりだ
I'm full of anxiety
もうやめようって泣いた日もあった
There were days I cried saying 'I'm quitting'
そんな時浮かんでくるの
In those times, they come to mind...
みんなの声が
everyone's voices
今までで一番
The most shining
輝く舞台
stage ever
ずっとなりたかった
I've always wanted to be
最強のアイドル
the strongest idol
今世界で一番幸せなアイドルから
From the happiest idol in the world right now
世界で一番の大好きをあげちゃう
I'll give you the number one 'I love you' in the world
些細な日常も
Even the trivial daily life
もっと大きなステージへ
towards an even bigger stage
まだまだ終わらない
It's not over yet
ありふれた奇跡を
An ordinary miracle
君と結んでゆく
I'll tie together with you
いけー！
Go!
ナム・ビ・オ・ジャ・パッ！　ツッコミも冴えて本日快晴
Nam-bi-o-ja-pa! My retort is sharp, today is clear skies
サボろ　夢ばかり手にするぜ全部 It's my grade
Let's slack off, I'll grab all those dreams, it's my grade
適当に頑張ろうぜ
Let's just do our best randomly
そんなん言ったっていいけどさ
You can say that, but...
必死に頑張ろうぜ
Let's do our best desperately
それが僕らじゃな？
Isn't that just who we are?
土砂降りじゃねえだわ
It's not a downpour.
そんでビンボーっちじゃねえだわ
And I'm not poor.
運搬児がバッチリ聴けてる
The delivery boy can hear it perfectly.
ニキになってる
He's becoming a 'Niki'.
かなたちゃん！
Kanata-chan!
全身全霊ちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome with all your heart and soul.
高まるかい？いっそちゃんと共感して
Is the excitement rising? Just empathize properly.
興奮し合おう　僕が呼んだもん
Let's get excited together, because I called for it.
翻弄するんだもん　現実越えろ未来
I'll toy with you, surpass reality, future!
Ah 逆転も平気！スイッチ入れちゃった
Ah, reversal is fine! I've flipped the switch.
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダーで
Namely, with Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der.
デモシモ面白がれること探し構えろ
Even if, find something fun and get ready.
返事聴かせてくれ
Let me hear your answer.
右左どこじゃない　突き抜けて行っちゃって
Not right or left, just pierce through.
詰まりたくらんだら　発射オーライだ
In short, if you've schemed, you're clear for takeoff.
ワクワク寸前さ！
On the verge of excitement!
聞いて、みんなと離れるのが寂しいのと
Listen, I'm sad to be leaving everyone and...
ガッキーの結婚が立ち直れてません
I haven't recovered from Gakky's marriage yet.
僕をアイドルにしてくれてみんな本当にありがとう！
Thank you everyone for making me an idol!
なんだよ、そんなこと言っちゃダメだ、おバカ！
What, you can't say things like that, you dummy!
わあ、すごい、ありがとう！
Wow, amazing, thank you!
響き合そうでんでんごまアウェイ
Resonating, spin like a top, away.
虎視眈々でいたいだもん
I want to be watchful for an opportunity.
だって意気昂々だもん
Because I'm in high spirits.
全方位がっつり当てが張っていらっしゃい
Come with full force from all directions.
いつでも心はちゃんと10代で
My heart is always in its teens.
いたいんだ好奇心絶えず熱心で
I want to stay that way, with constant curiosity and enthusiasm.
いたいんだって言い聞かせるんだ
I tell myself I want to stay that way.
調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうから
Because if I get carried away, people will get tired of me soon.
あー買い取んなら横暴どんと来い！ですって
Ah, if you're buying, come at me with your tyranny!
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダーで
Namely, with Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der.
しがみつけ努力とは最後まで諦めないこと
Cling to it, effort means not giving up until the end.
見守っておいて
Please keep an eye on me.
本当はBaby　自信がないよ
To be honest Baby, I have no confidence.
本当はBaby　不安ばかりで泣きそうだぜ
To be honest Baby, I'm so anxious I could cry.
おねがいBaby　くじけないって決めたの
Please Baby, I've decided not to give up.
だからBaby　挑戦したいよ未開の天地
So Baby, I want to challenge uncharted territory.
無限のフィールで！
In an infinite field!
全身全霊ちゃんと歓迎して
Welcome with all your heart and soul.
高まるかい？いっそちゃんと共感して
Is the excitement rising? Just empathize properly.
興奮し合おう　僕が呼んだもん
Let's get excited together, because I called for it.
翻弄するんだもん　現実越えろ未来
I'll toy with you, surpass reality, future!
Ah 逆転も平気！スイッチ入れちゃった
Ah, reversal is fine! I've flipped the switch.
すなわち特者生存ワンダラダーで
Namely, with Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der.
でもしもおもしろがれること探し放題で
And if, you can find as many fun things as you want.
無限のフィールだね
It's an infinite field, isn't it?
ハプニングしなくてもいい
It's okay if nothing happens.
ど真ん中一直線
Straight through the center.
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer.
胸を張り今を生きるその意味を
With pride, the meaning of living in the now.
明くる日もくるくる日も確かめ進め！
Day after day, day after day, confirm it and move forward!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
みんなー、ありがとうございましたー！
Everyone, thank you very much!
えー、聴いていただいたのは、オリ曲メドレー、メドレーにしました。
Well, what you just heard was an original song medley. I made it into a medley.
繋ぎましたよ。
I connected them.
そして「世界で一番のアイドル」、作詞をしました。
And "The Best Idol in the World", I wrote the lyrics.
この時は卒業だって考えてなかったから、
At that time I wasn't even thinking about graduating,
本当に、あの、いっぱい聴いてほしい曲で、
so it's a song I really want you to listen to a lot.
そして「特者生存ワンダラダー！！」でした！
And that was "Tokusha Seizon Wonder-la-der!!"
はい、これを初めてね、出したね。え、オリジナル楽曲ですけれども。
Yes, I released this for the first time. Well, it's an original song.
ちょっと語りたいこといっぱいあるんですけど、
There's a lot I want to talk about,
やっぱりあの服だよね。
but it's got to be that outfit, right?
ってことで、1秒着替えてきました！
So, I've done a one-second costume change!
はい、やっぱりこれだよね、みんな。
Yes, it has to be this, everyone.
ヘイ、こんかなた！
Hey, Kon-kanata!
キャッチコピーは握力50キロ、ギュッギュに握りつぶしちゃうぞ。
My catchphrase is: with a grip strength of 50kg, I'll crush you tight.
ホロライブ4期生、かなたんこと天音かなたです！
Hololive 4th generation, known as Kanatan, I'm Amane Kanata!
はい、ということでね、録画...危ないことは、危ない橋は渡らないでおきまして、
Right, so... recordings... let's not take any risks,
今のような、あの、感じでいきたいと思うんですけれども、
I'd like to continue with this kind of vibe,
もう本当にオリジナル楽曲は、フェスやイベント、ソロライブなど...
but really, original songs at festivals, events, solo lives...
他にもたくさんの思い出が詰まっていて、
There are so many other memories packed in here.
みんながね、たくさん聴いてくれたおかげと言いますか、本当にありがとうございました...と思っています。
I suppose it's thanks to everyone listening so much... thank you so very much, that's what I feel.
えー、みんなね、あの、この後ですね、22時10分から、最後の歌ってみた。
Um, everyone, after this, at 22:10, I'll be posting my last cover song.
みんなと約束してました。あの、動画消えちゃって歌い直そうって言っていたね、
I promised you all. Since the video was deleted and I said I'd sing it again,
あの、KINGを投稿するので、絶対見てくださいね！
I'll be posting 'KING,' so please be sure to watch it!
毎日一緒にいてくれたへい民、ホロライブの大好きなメンバーたち、
To the Heimin who stayed with me every day, my beloved members of hololive,
そしてたくさん支えてくださった本当にお世話になった方々、全ての方に感謝しています。
and all the people who supported and took care of me, I'm grateful to everyone.
夢のような時間は本当にありがとうございました。心、口...ここで噛むのね。
Thank you so much for this dream-like time. My heart, my mou... I'm tripping over my words here.
子供の頃のアイドルになりたいという夢が、作詞作曲をしてみたいという夢を叶えました。
My childhood dream of becoming an idol and my dream of songwriting and composing have come true.
そして、最後の曲ですが、まだ歌うんですよ。僕が初めて作詞作曲した楽曲があります。
And for the last song, I'm still singing. There's a piece I wrote and composed for the first time.
今はいない同期、ココの卒業に合わせて、
For the graduation of our genmate who's no longer here, Coco,
4期生のトワ、ルーナ、わために捧げた楽曲です。
this is a song I dedicated to Towa, Luna, and Watame of the 4th gen.
前を向いて、笑顔で、この楽曲で活動を最後にしたいと思います。
I want to end my activities with this song, looking forward and with a smile.
それでは聴いてください、キセキ結び。
Please listen, Kiseki Musubi.
キセキ結び / 作詞・作曲 天音かなた 編曲 ハム
Kiseki Musubi / Lyrics & Composition: Amane Kanata, Arrangement: Ham
約束しようよ 僕らが出会えたキセキ
Let's make a promise, the miracle that brought us together
忘れないように
So we never forget
夢抱いて集う 青春アニメみたいな
Gathering with dreams, like a youth anime
ハッピーなエンドになる彼方へ飛ぶよ
Flying towards a future where there's a happy ending
寝ぼけ眼 あくびして 今日は何をしようか
Sleepy-eyed and yawning, what should we do today?
永遠に続く海を駆けるケルン
A cairn crossing the sea that goes on forever
今は溜息よりも勇気を
For now, give me courage over sighs
諦めるなんてないの ここで歌う
There's no giving up, I'll sing right here
僕の声は聞こえてますか？
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
Reaching out to you
学校の友達じゃ きっと出会えなかった
We surely wouldn't have met as school friends
画面の先の遥か遠くまで
To the vast distance beyond the screen
ささくれた言葉も 誰かの笑顔になる
Even frayed words can become someone's smile
それぞれの色で 星結ぶキセキ
Connecting stars with each of our colors, a miracle
キラキラ輝くステージに 連れて行くよ
I'll take you to the sparkling stage
泣いて笑ってはしゃいで 毎日ジェットコースター
Crying, laughing, having fun, every day is a roller coaster
たまには寝転んで お昼寝しよう
Sometimes let's just lie down and take a nap
ちょっと自信ない時 お隣で応援して
When I lack a bit of confidence, cheer me on from by my side
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと 許してね
Just for today, please forgive me for crying
未来の僕がアルバム開く
My future self opens the album
傷ついた写真だって 宝物だ
Even the hurt photos are treasures
僕の愛が見えていますか？
Can you see my love?
君に届け
Reaching out to you
顔も個性も 性格も違うけれど
Our faces, personalities, and characters are different, but...
弱気な時は目蓋 ギュッと瞑り
When feeling weak, I close my eyes tight
もう1回、もう1回、絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, I'll never give up
前の背中追う 下手っぴな僕でも
Even if I'm clumsy and just following the back in front of me...
君の隣にいたくて 走るの
I run because I want to be by your side
誰にも言えずに 描いた夢がたとえ叶わないとしても
Even if the dream I drew without telling anyone doesn't come true...
ボロボロの靴でも カッコよくなくても
Even with worn-out shoes, even if I'm not cool...
あぁ、幼いあの日の僕ならなんて言う？ 「止まらないで」
Ah, what would the young me from that day say? "Don't stop"
初めて僕ら出会った日 まるで昨日みたいに思い出すけど
I remember the day we first met as if it were yesterday, but...
もう行こうか 最後になぜ重なる
Let's go now, why do they overlap at the end...
キセキ
The miracles...
僕の声は聞こえてますか？
Can you hear my voice?
君に届け
Reaching out to you
黒板のメッセージ 桜の中をくぐって
The message on the blackboard, passing through the cherry blossoms...
...声を聴いて
...hear your voice
ずっと ずっと
Forever and ever
嬉しい日 楽しい日
Happy days, fun days
悲しい日 別れの日も
Sad days, even days of parting
それぞれの色で
With their own colors
星結ぶ奇跡
A star-connecting miracle
キラキラ輝くステージで
On this sparkling stage
約束しよう
Let's make a promise
いつか ここで
That someday, here
また会おう
We'll meet again
みんな... ありがとう
Everyone... thank you.
ホロライブ所属、アイドルの天音かなたでした。
I was your idol, Amane Kanata, from Hololive.
6年間 本当に幸せな日々でした。
These six years have been truly happy days.
へい民、不器用な僕を応援してくれてありがとう。
Heimin, thank you for supporting someone as clumsy as me.
ずっとずっと大好きだよ。
I'll always, always love you.
ずっとずっと家族だよ。
We'll always, always be family.
みんな本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you everyone, truly, for everything!
ありがとう
Thank you.